There seem to be too many
poor people around lately!
What do you mean?
Whoever you stop, find nothing
worthwhile. Just pennies.
Listen, Ajamila...
You weren't always... like this...
Like what?
Well... involved in
what you are doing now.
Why do you ask?
Just curious.
Yes, there was
a different Ajamila once...
A different life...
everything was different.
What did you do?
I was a Brahmin...
A priest.
...and then he rushes to Prahlada,
shakes him by the shoulders and screams:
"Where, where is your Vishnu? Show Him!"
And Prahlada?
Prahlada looks into his eyes
and replies with a smile:
"Dear father, look closely,
and you'll see the Lord everywhere."
And then?
And then Hiranyakashipu screams:
"So, your Vishnu is in my house?"
Fish... So much... Why?
Prahlada replies with a smile:
Why? You asked for fish!
"Yes, father, the Lord
is always in our home."
Fry some fish for yourself,
Varsha. And for me...
Then Hiranyakashipu grabs his sword
and starts swinging it, shouting:
Did I hear that right?
"Vishnu! Vishnu! If You're here, come out!"
You heard right.
And when Hiranyakashipu saw no one,
he rushed at Prahlada
with his sword, saying:
You're changing, Ajamila.
"If your Vishnu doesn't appear before me now,
I'll cut off your head!"
And Prahlada?
Prahlada, this little boy,
tells his father:
You never used to eat fish...
What happened?
"Here He is, my Lord,
right before you."
Hiranyakashipu points to a pillar and yells:
A new Ajamila has appeared.
"Is he in this pillar?"
The old one is gone.
"Yes, father, can't you see?"
Then Hiranyakashipu grabs
his sword and with all his might
strikes the pillar...
So, how was your day? Successful?
But you know, Ajamila,
no one heard the sound of the broken pillar
Why?
Because at that moment,
there was a deafening roar of a lion,
...and the magnificent Lord Vishnu appeared.
Although, you don't have to say,
your face says it all.
They fought for a long time
before Lord Narasimhadev
grabbed Hiranyakashipu,
laid him on his knees
and with his sharp claws
tore him to pieces.
Was today successful?
Absolutely!
And so saved his dear devotee Prahlada.
And would the Lord do the same for me?
Come to me and save me from demons?
Of course, Ajamila.
The Lord's love never ceases.
Dear sir, are you playing fair?
You want to insult me,
esteemed one?
Even if we forget about Him,
Honesty is my middle name!
Well then, let's play.
He continues to love us.
Now we're talking!
And do you have money?
And is always ready to come to our aid.
Of course, I do.
This... this... this is so wonderful.
Dice don't like playing for nothing!
Dice need respect!
Yes, my son. This is the ultimate truth.
So, shall we play?
Father, are you okay?
Yes, my boy, I'm fine, just a bad omen.
I've won!
Alright! You're lucky today.
Move aside, let another try.
Father
What, my boy?
Father, tell Swamiji about
what I asked you today.
I want to play too!
I'll bet one coin!
Ah, yes,
During our pilgrimage,
Ajamila made an important decision
Alright... let's go!
He wants to receive initiation from you.
Well done...
Oh Gurudev, please accept me
as a disciple.
Brother, you're lucky today...
I ask you for this mercy.
I will not leave this path.
Never?
Never!
One more time!
Well, Lochan Babu, gather your son.
If only luck would come my way...
Tomorrow I want to see him in my ashram.
Gurudev, so you've accepted me?
Of course, my boy.
Father, did you hear?
Maybe I should play too?
Maybe I'll get lucky?
Yes, my boy, yes, wonderful!
Ah, pity I didn't bring money...
I would have played too...
Ajamila…
Yes, Gurudev.
Today marks a wonderful day, long awaited.
Well...well...well...
What did he roll?
Are you ready to be devoted to the truth
in all circumstances of your life,
Ah, he lost!
I knew it, he's a loser.
and be faithful to the Brahmanical vows?
Tough luck for you...
I am ready, Gurudev.
Do you promise to follow the spiritual path
It's alright, honorable one,
next time you'll get luck...
until the end of your days?
Let's get out of here, why stand,
gawking? Let's go.
I promise, Gurudev
Name me the Brahmanical qualities
you will exhibit.
Come on, hold on...
Honesty, purity, ability
to perform austerities,
Money and greed -
a beautiful combination,
calmness, freedom from anger, forgiveness,
non-violence towards any living being.
when you know how to use them.
How's our baby?
He's moving non-stop.
Married to a Brahmin.
Who would imagine?
Ajamila.
Yes, father.
Have you forgotten
what you have to do today?
What are you talking about?
Ah, tomorrow we will perform...
Tomorrow at dawn
we will perform an auspicious ceremony.
Of course, I remember.
I haven't forgotten at all.
Good day, pilgrims.
So, you should go to the forest right now
Peace be upon you, good sir.
Where are you heading?
for suitable firewood.
We're visiting holy places.
Clean, dry, an elbow's length…
Heading to blessed Prayag now.
…pleasant to the eye.
Right.
Our pilgrimage has come to an end.
Also, you should bring forest flowers.
Let's rest today, take a bath,
and tomorrow... tomorrow we will
Clean, pleasant to the eye,
and with a good fragrance.
perform auspicious rituals
and feed the Brahmins.
Right. But don't smell them!
Right! To mark the end
of our journey!
As the sacred texts say.
Go right now, you'll be back by lunchtime.
And after lunch, we have
some chores to do.
Why are you, a healthy man, leading
the blind and give them your time?
You're like in prison with them!
You're not your own master.
Walking with them, caring for them.
You can't leave them even for a minute.
What else is human life for?
If not to help others and serve the Lord?
How else should we our time?
Time should be spent wisely.
Not wandering aimlessly.
These people are my destiny.
Together, we visit holy places
and pray to the Lord.
Dad, you're a Brahmin yourself,
are you going to give
gifts to yourself?
Even though we're Brahmins,
we too must engage in charity
and use all money for
serving the Lord and holy people.
Now let's check your bags,
shake your clothes a little.
Maybe a coin will jingle!
No! These people will leave in peace!
And we won't touch anyone!
What? Can't do it yourself,
don't stop us.
Look at the brahmin one...
What? Right here? Now? Are you sure?
So, so... aha... what's this?
Come on, let's see...
Please! My Goddess! Do you want me dead?
Come on, show me, what's in your bag?
Goddess, am I a goddess? Is this gold?
Maybe hiding something
in your turban? Come on, show it!
Gold! All gold! Yes, Goddess!
Aha, what about you?
Take it! All the gold in the world! All yours!
You too, turn around.
Look at this, said
they were poor pilgrims!
Please be kind to me!
Yes? Goddess!
Look, I found a coin too.
Yes, my fool!
Look at that, not bad...
Here you go...
Alright, go now...
Father, I can't take it anymore. Where is he?
...I don't know.
Father, what should we do?
A whole day has passed,
and he's still not back.
Ajamila, what in the world?
First, calm down. Sit, eat.
In our profession, your cowardice
can cost a life.
You haven't eaten anything
since morning.
Either you're with us or
go to hell.
A whole day has passed.
The sun is about to set,
and he's still not back.
So?
Okay...
Okay what?
What if something happened to him?
What if he was attacked by robbers?
I'm with you...
There are always many robbers in the forest!
Or what if he was bitten by a snake?
No!
It was a scorpion.
That's good, Ajamila.
But remember...
There are always many poisonous
scorpions in the forest.
And now my Ajamila
There won't be a second time.
lies in the grass, dying from its venom.
I will go look for him!
Well, say something to me.
What?
Well, make something up.
You are so vocal, after all.
Brahman
Sorry, dear, I have to go.
Who are you?
Won't you say a word?
Om Tat Sat
Swaha. Purnahuti.
Why should I?
I want to hear about
your passion one more time.
You'll hear it.
Leave them! Empty...
Later.
But I want it now.
Later. I'm in a hurry.
Om Tat Sat
Well, tell me I'm a goddess.
Well, goddess.
Om Tat Sat
Not like that! Say it as you did before!
Like this: "My Goddess"!
I didn't say that.
Let's better go to Prayag!
What?
Like this "My Goddess" - I never said that.
Of cource, on foot
I didn't say it like that!
Got is with us
Didn't say it? Ah, you rascal!
Get away from me.
Brahman, now robber...
Calm down! Everything's fine.
Nothing happened.
Not fine! You're cold-hearted!
With a knife. And they're pilgrims...
A stone, that's who you are!
Can't even be nice to me.
Damn me, brahmand Ajamila!
Yes, I can be nice... But later.
Damn me!
Then we'll talk later.
So, in a week?.. My goddess?
Go away.
Bye then.
No daughter, you're not going
to the forest alone. Sit down!
How can I just sit and do nothing?
I cannot live without him.
I will pray. I hope he returns soon.
Ah, daughter, daughter.
My heart hurts like never before.
Who invented that wine?
Something terrible has happened to him.
Father, I feel something terrible.
It's tough with it, and without.
You... so beautiful... like a flower...
What, can't get yesterday's
blind men out of your head?
Flower! And everyone tells me I'm a goddess!
It was hard for me at first too.
How can it be - they're
holy pilgrims, and we rob them.
Are you talking about that man?..
Who is he to you?
And then?
Man? So, you saw him, Ajamila?
Then I got used to it, it became easier.
It's my job, and their fate.
I did.
The past doesn't let go easily.
And now what?
It will let go.
I don't know.
Yeah, the sooner the better.
But I know. Shall I tell?
Lean in to me. I'll whisper it in your ear.
Give me the money!
Do you hear me? Or I'll finish off
your whole miserable family!
Where's the money, I said!
You probably also want to be with me here,
in the forest, where no one sees us?..
You probably also want me to love you?
You know, I'm ready.
Because I like you.
Do you hear me? I'm ready, Ajamila. I'm Ready.
I will be very happy if you wear this.
This is for you.
For me?
How lovely!
Thank you.
Why are you silent? Do you hear me?
No… No!
Where did you get it?
Well, no then.
Doesn't matter. It's for you.
Run home.
And if you change your mind, and want
to find me... you'll find
I know you didn't buy it.
But you know I can't
wear this on the streets.
Someone will surely recognize
their jewelry.
only…
what?
Then why did you bring it?
Money
what?
Money. Coins. My love costs something.
Listen, your craft is
becoming very dangerous.
The town is buzzing with talk
about robbers in the forest.
And if you don't find it - no need,
Brahman Ajamila.
The king has already sent
a squad of his best warriors,
to catch the robbers
and bring them to trial.
And the king has already come up with
most terrible punishment for them...
What is that?
The king ordered the robbers
have their hands and feet severed.
But spare their lifes
as a warning to others.
God! God! Is this a dream? No
Did this happen to me?
I have my wife Kamali! Father... My path!
What's happening to me?
Ajamila?! Where have you been? I almost died…
Ajamila. What's wrong with you?
What happened?
Nothing happened.
Where were you?
Collecting wood, flowers.
So better get rid of them...
Give them to jewelers to melt it down.
Why did it take so long?
Long? No, I was quick.
Still, Ajamila, why so long?
Nothing happened!
It just turned out that way.
Everything is fine with me!
Fine! All is good!
Ajamila!
Brahman Ajamila!
I know you have money!
There! Give it to me,
and you'll get something in return…
I'm ready, Ajamila. Ready.
Come to me! Forget everyone.
Now you have only me in your life!
I will give you what you've never experienced.
Just come to me…
Why didn't we meet earlier?
We are made for each other.
Didn't you realize that after our meeting?
I am your fate. I am your real life…
My embrace is gentler than your wife's.
Right, Ajamila? Don't deceive yourself.
I am much more skilled in love than she is.
And how sweet are my lips!
What are you waiting for?
Kamali... is that you?
Taste them!
Kamali... how... why...
Sir, you're mistaken.
That woman is dead.
I'm just a simple beggar.
Sir, we're just beggars.
Go on your way.
You don't belong here.
Ajamila, Kamali's fate
is on your head...
Prabhu, are you awake?
Don't forget that...
Sir, you're mistaken.
That woman is dead...
Why aren't you getting up?
Are you waiting for me?
Yes.
Kamali, get up, we need
to perform the ritual today.
We need to prepare.
Yes, we do!
Hello Varsha.
You probably also want me to love you?
I see... brought the debt?
Yes, of course!
You know, I'm ready. Because I like you.
Do you hear me?
Ajamila!
Good! What else?
I missed you.
Missed me? Maybe also say
you're crazy about me,
Purnahuti
And that you can't live
without me?
Exactly.
The Lord joyfully entered your home.
So maybe you'll even
marry me, huh?
Let him stay here forever,
and bring prosperity and peace with him.
I am your destiny. I am your real life…
Your blessings warm my heart.
Thank you for them…
And you are a lucky man!
You have such a son — Ajamila!
My embrace is gentler than your wife's embrace.
Right, Ajamila?
Maybe you'll let
an old friend inside?
Yes... Ajamila is my hope!
I want him to become better than me.
What are you waiting for? Taste them!
What if Ajamila comes?
Ajamila!.. Ajamila!
Good sign, Ajamila!
The Lord sends us a good sign.
He won't come.
But what if he does?
By the way!
Father, look
how beautiful it is here!
What... what are you doing?
To you and your son,
with heartfelt gratitude, Lochan Babu.
Wait! Wait! I'll give you
all the money!
Son, my boy...
Money! Money… Coins…!
He's dead. You killed him.
My love costs something…
What makes you say that?
Hey! Get up! Wake up!
…He will have beautiful eyes like yours…
Wake up, open your eyes...
And let the chin be like his grandfather's.
Okay.
He will have beautiful long fingers…
...I didn't mean to...
And when he grows up, he will be tall,
even taller than you…
didn't mean to...
no... no... not this...
Kamali, do you really think this is possible?
His wife and children are waiting...
Do you have children?
My mother always said,
that parents should first imagine their child,
and only then give birth.
The Lord will definitely give us such a son,
as we create in our minds.
Ajamila, it's actually so simple!
Dad, are you leaving already?
Will you bring gifts?
Well… maybe…
Let's sit down here!
Madhava, Gopala… Narayana!
Will you take this money
to your family?
Don't start moralizing me!
Don't talk to me about ethics!
That's what we will call him, Ajamila…
Our son…
I know everything myself!
I didn't mean to kill! Didn't want to!
Our little one… our treasure.
I only need money!
Nothing else! Just the money!
Narayana. It's so affectionate. My Narayana!
I don't need your miserable lives!
I don't need anything! Nothing!
Have you already imagined him?
Of course! I imagine him well.
Will you take this money to your family?
Do you think they'll be happier?
How do you manage that?
What?
Well… imagining, what his eyes,
what his hands will be like.
You want to make some happy,
by killing and bringing grief to others?
what name we'll give him.
I just close my eyes and see all this…
Well, I'm out... I have to go...
Yes, of course.
Kamali, dear, let's go home.
Home, why? We are having such a good time walking.
I'm feeling unwell.
Here, take this.
Something feels not right…
Is your head hurting?
Prabhu, do you even hear me?
Huh? What? Ah… I hear you, I hear.
Yes, I hear you…
Now everything will be fine.
You will feel better soon.
Just lie down a bit, and you'll feel better.
Oh Lord, what's happening to me?
This has never happened before.
Why can't I get her out of my head?
I don't want this! Where is my mind?
Where is my piety? What am I doing?
I think we'll have another son.
It's not too late to stop!
What, Ajamila? We already
have so many sons.
My wife, my Kamali, I can't treat her like this.
I want us to have a daughter.
You probably also want to be with me
here in the forest, where no one sees us?
And we'll name her... Kumari.
Because you like me…
In honor of
Lord Mahadeva's wife, right?
…And if you want to find me, you will….
…My love costs something….
Prabhu, I respect the sages,
but I'd really love our son
to have the name of the Lord
but...
No! Don't argue! The name of God!
Please. Don't argue.
Alright, alright.
Madhava... Gopala... Narayana!
What Narayana?
That will be his name, Ajamila...
Our son...
Our little boy...
Our treasure.
Narayana!
No.
Our son's name will be Narayana...
That will bring us luck.
Forgive me… I can't… Her hands… Voice… I can't…
Ajamila, if you want
to philosophize, go outside.
I will sleep.
Dad! Dad! You're back!
I love you my boy!
I love you too, dad.
Where are your brothers?
They went to the river.
Why didn't you go with them?
I's boring with them.
I was waiting for you, dad.
Well, you know, if you have money - come in, but if not…
Not today, but there will be tomorrow… You know that.
Dad, dad catch!
When you have some, then you can come…
You can't treat me like this,
Dad, come on throw it… come on…
Dad, seriously...
I won't leave you today,
I've left everything to come to you…
Let me go! It hurts!
Let me go… And stop acting like a prude!
Dad, that's not fair!
Always be on guard!
Then you can win!
Let her go!
Who are you?
Well, come in since you've come. I've been waiting!
Now I understand why you didn't want to let me in!
You were waiting for this… Brahman…
And what about you?
Me? Oh, I will leave and never come back again.
And you… Very soon
…Will turn into… .
Why are you so sad, dad?
Well?
You'll become an old woman no one needs!
Nothing... all fine.
Be happy, Brahman.
...I'll go...
take some rest...
We'll meet again.
Ajamila…. Why did you do that…
You killed me, Ajamila…
Well, hello, Brahman Ajamila.
Hello… uh…
Varsha. That's my name.
Be damned… Are you happy now?
Ajamila… Ajamila…
Hello, Varsha.
I thought Brahmans sleep at this time.
But look, Brahmans are fully awake and wandering.
Why did you do that?
Now you will have a different life…
So…
You're not in a hurry?
Come with us… Ajamila….
Well then, I am not in a hurry either… Let's go…
Don't touch me!
You robbed me...
You betrayed me!
Leave me alone…
I didn't mean to kill you…
Don't touch... Murderer...
Stop, go away!
I didn't want to, didn't want to!
Be damned...
Why...
Ajamila…
Well, come to me…
What happened, son?
You fainted. And mom said
that you had a stroke...
Ajamila!
Yes, Gurudev…
Once long ago, I asked you…
Are you ready to follow
the principles of religion to the end of your life
…What did you answer me then?
Narayana, my boy!
Do not leave me.
That I am ready, Gurudev…
I'm scared!
I love you Narayana
I love your mom
your brothers
Out of love for you
I've done many things...
which is why I'm so scared now…
Money! Where's the money?
Give me the money!
Or I'll finisy all your
miserable family!!
Where is the money I ask?
I need more! Give me all the money!
Would the Lord do that for me?
Father, did you hear?
Ajamila...
I will not leave this path!
Never? Never!
And you will get something in return...
It's all my fault...
Well come to me...
Sir, you are mistaken.
That woman died.
Go bring me rice, fish, vegetables -
I have nothing to feed the children!
I hate you, I hate you!!
Hate you! Hate you!!
You, it's because of you!
Shut up! Better remember
who came to me first.
Who told me about love?
Promised something?
Brought me money
5 silver coins?
Who searched for me all night
like a madman?
Ajamila, is that all? What else?
Who brought me here?
It was you, Ajamila, you!
So you better shut it!
You were gone almost a day,
you come and calmly go to sleep?
I just helped you to fulfill
what you dreamed of!
Did you forget anything?
No, Ajamila.
Now you will explain everything to me.
Dad, is everything okay?
Where have you been?
Why did you make me and your wife worry?
Too late.
And where is the money that was donated to us?
It's too late to change anything.
It was my money!
I earned it! And now forget it!
There's no more money.
How dare you raise your voice at me?
My life is coming to an end.
Leave me alone!
I've done too much
that won't let me die in peace.
Let's go, daughter…
Let it be…
Where were you?
And where is the money that was donated to us?
It was my money, I earned it,
forget about it, there's no more money!
Leave me alone!
Father!
Yes. A little...
Where are you going?
Money won't fall from the sky on us.
Yes, that's for sure.
You left me early in the morning,
and now look — it's noon.
Only a little time has passed…
I wanted to sleep, but I couldn't.
They didn't let me...
Who didn't let you?
Well... father... and... wife.
Whose wife?
Mine.
So you're married?
Yes, but it's nothing serious.
Well, if it's not serious for you,
it's even less so for me.
Thief! Thief! Get out of here!
Murderer! Go away! Thief!
That's the same godless man!
Look at this rascal!
Thief! Thief! This is not a place for you!
Came with a child and thinks
everyone will forget about what he did?
Get out! Get out of here!
Go where you were going!
This is not a place for you!
Who do you think we are?
Don't even come near us!
So, you have a family... Good...
Go, go! Get away from here!
Look what he's thinking!
And what did you tell them?
Leave! You've completely lost your mind!
This is our place! This is our place!
This is our place! Rascal!
There's nothing for you here! Yes Yes!
What could I tell them?
Why did they drive us away?
Why do they hate you so much?
Do you not care?
...this is their place, son.
We're not welcomed there.
...Probably not.
Though now it's easier.
so what? No one can claim the road
for themselves. It is public!
Just three days ago,
it was very hard for me.
But then something changed.
It's okay, son. It's okay.
I'll sit by myself. You go.
Something inside me burned out.
I no longer want to think
and weigh every step.
And to be afraid of what others will say.
I've done that my whole life.
I want to breathe freely,
to live without fear and remorse.
You go.
I can stay with you, dad.
After that meeting with you...
there, in the forest...
I won't be bored.
I will sing. Sa! Re! Ha! Ma!
I couldn't think of anything else but you.
No, son, you better go.
Neither my family nor my duties,
Come back for me in the evening.
— nothing could make me forget you...
I need to be alone...
your hands... your voice... your eyes...
Okay, dad. I will go.
Wait for me, don't get lonely.
I don't want to play the role of
a faithful husband and loving son,
when here inside me is a burning fire.
Hello, beggar Ajamila!
I can't, and I don't want to...
Today your new life begins.
I just want to be with you...
only with you...
So what... have you fallen in love with me?
Yes...
Have you really found something special in me?
Oh! You don't even know how wonderful you are!
You are my perfection.
You are life itself to me!
I just can't live without you!
I want to be only with you... only with you...
Where is he?
I just saw Ajamila...
He went into the house of a well-known harlot.
Is it hard for you, Ajamila?
I thought so.
Will you follow him?
You are not young anymore...
Must have seen a lot, haven't you?
No. He couldn't be held back by a young wife,
Yes, I've seen a lot.
nor by the path of religion he has followed for so long.
You wanted happiness, but instead
you're afraid to look people in the eye.
If he has made his choice, what can I do?
I know...
It's all my fault.
You chose this life for yourself.
...stop it!
Why are you tormenting me?
I invested everything I had in Ajamila.
Don't you need help?
I'm not young, I have
a heavy burden on my back.
But he made his own choice.
In an instant, the Lord rid me of my pride,
Only death will help.
my hopes, my expectations...
My good name...
All I can do now is pray
that the Lord doesn't leave him.
Here we are, Ajamila!
We've been waiting for you
for so long!
Who, who are you?
Your new friends!..
Don't be afraid of us!...
What do you want from me?
So what are we going to do?
Where are you going, we haven't
properly introduced ourselves yet.
What do you mean?
No, no... Where... Don't...
Where are you dragging me?
You've been living with me
for several days now...
Your money has long run out.
Home! To the underworld! It's time
appear before Yamaraja's court!
And you don't have any new money.
And all my... admirers...
You chased them away...
No... I haven't finished yet,
I still have so much to do...
If you're worried about money,
that's not a problem for me.
All your work is already finished...
Really? That's good news.
I have a family, I have a little son.
Yes. It was never a problem for me.
Narayana!! Narayana!! Narayana!!!
Stop!
And where will we live?
Who are you?
Live?..
And how dare you interfere with us...
The servants of Yamaraja himself?
We can live at my place.
God of death!
We are the messengers of
the Supreme Lord Narayana!
I will bring you to my house.
Release this man,
he is no longer in your power!
You'll have a separate room.
Release whom, Ajamila?
If you agree to be with me -
I'll provide for you.
Yes, the Earth did not know
a greater sinner than him.
He was a Brahman, but he got involved with
a prostitute and became a thief and murderer!
Tell me, do Brahmans chant something every day?
The darkest, most terrifying regions
of hell await for him!
You have some mantras, don't you?
Ajamila has already atoned for
all his sins!
Three times a day…
A hymn to praise the Sun God…
In despair, he spoke
the Holy Name of Lord Narayana!
Three times a day.
And when was the last time you chanted them?
Sins are atoned by tough
austerities and penances!
Well, probably last week.
And what he spoke the Holy Name
is accidental!
He was just calling his son!
Yes Yes!!
And that was the last time.
Because then you found love?
Like fire burns dry grass to ashes,
so is the Holy Name of the Lord -
burns away all the sinful reactions,
Oh come on, I really do love you.
even if it is said unintentionally.
Love... I believe...
You don't just give up everything like that...
You must release this man!
And I don't...
Okay, you win!
Okay, okay. I understand...
Well, buddy,
we'll see you soon!
Tell your family that I am... a maid.
If they believe it, of course.
We'll come back for you.
Tell your wife...
Lord... Lord... I've done nothing
worthwile in my entire life,
Although, say whatever you want...
But remember, I won't work for you.
I only sinned, I only tarnished
the family of Brahmins...
You will be the one bringing money to me...
But You, You've sent
your great servants,
For my love... Got it?
and they were able to save me
from the hands of death. You saved me…
We still have time...
how shall we spend it?
Come up to me, I'll whisper it in your ear.
I promise you - this old Ajamila
will never forget you again!
You know how much I adore you...
I promise to never again
return to my past life!
Never! Never!
You gave me another chance!
Your Holy Name saved me.
Your Holy Name is infinitely
merciful…
Dad, dad, wait!
The city is the opposite way!
I'm leaving, son. I'm leaving to
dedicate my life to the Lord.
Lord Narayana?
Yes, son. Lord Narayana.
Where will you go?
I lived my life in vain,
I spent so many years in sin
Ajamila... You have come!
You have returned!
Now I am leaving for Haridwar, Narayana.
To stay there forever.
Is this your wife?
And never, never
ever stop serving the Lord...
Prabhu... Who is this woman?
Kamali, meet Varsha.
I'm leaving, son.
Goodbye Narayana...
Why has she come to our house?
Goodbye son...
She will help you with the household.
Prabhu, am I not managing by myself?
So what, I am going to live here?
Dad, dad...
Yes...
And... she... where will she live?
There...
Ajamila, I need a bed here.
I need shelves for clothes,
and boxes for jewelry.
You will buy me jewelry, won't you?
I remember, you promised…
And tell her not to hover over me.
This is now my home too.
And we will live here together.
Wait... Where are you going to?
Now, every time she wants to cry,
you'll run to comfort her?
Do you think that's normal?
She is my wife!
And so? I need attention too.
You don't want me to get upset, do you?
Alright
I want to spend this night in the yard.
I can no longer and do not want
to stay in this house.
Bring out a bed for me.
Ajamila, come to your father.
What is it, father?
My time has come, there is no one else
for me to think about but the Lord.
And I won't stay here anymore.
I will leave... I hope
it will be easier for you.
Let's go, daughter...
Ajamila, it's getting dark.
It's time for us to go to bed.
And you know -
I need all your attention and care.
Alright. Ajamila,
I am waiting for you...
I am waiting for you…
Father... Father... why?
It hurts so much!
It is so painful for me!
The stars are so beautiful tonight!
They have always been like this,
as long as I can remember.
I look at them every day.
My days are not like one another,
but the stars always remain the same.
Oh Supreme Lord, Master of my life,
You are unchanging,
like the stars in the sky.
And unchanging is Your love for us.
Yet we, blinded by our own pain,
cannot see Your love in our lives...
Oh my Narayana, oh Merciful One,
I ask You,
help me to open my heart
enter into it...
I am waiting for You...
Who is there?
My Lord, is it You?
I see You... I recognize You!
How beautiful You are...
You have come for me...
You Yourself have come for me!..
I am ready to go.
Father! Father! Father!
Your father died last night.
Father!
I pray to the Almighty that He gives you
spiritual wisdom and strength
to never stray from the path of
righteousness and virtue.
Do not leave me, I need your strength.
My blessings will never leave you, son,
you can always count on me.
And you will come to see me
in the ashram, won't you?
Of course, son... We will see
each other constantly.
That's good, that's so good!
Father! What have I done?
...what have I done...
Not only your father died tonight...
Tonight, your wife also died.
What?.. What are you saying, Kamali?..
The Kamali who once married Ajamila,
a man of duty and honor
No longer exists.
I can no longer stay here...
I want to leave.
Are you letting me go?
I let you go... Kamali...
Thank you, Prabhu. Please forgive me.
I couldn't be the wife you deserved.
No... you were everything to me...
Kamali... Kamali...
Forgive me if you can.
We've run out of money.
I know, you've told me already.
And I need something from the clothes.
Yesterday, they gave me a piece of fabric, a pot of oil, and five silver coins.
What can we give to the temple from this?
I think, three coins.
Take these coins and give them to the head priest.
Yes, father.
Daughter, will two coins and a pot of oil last us a week?
Of course, father.
What shall we do?
I don't know, I'll go now and think of something.
Will you think of something?
Maybe it's better I think of something?
Maybe I should invite someone over?
What?
Drop it! Figured it out! No guests!
I'll provide for you! And forget about your old craft!
Do you think this junk is worth anything?
Doubtful.
Then why do you need it?
I'll try to exchange it for a measure of rice.
A measure of rice!
Listen, dear, besides rice, do you plan to feed me anything else?
Could have brought home some fresh fish...
Varsha, I've told you so many times!
What about Varsha, what? You don't want fish, fine.
But I do!
Fried... a bit spicy... mmm, it's so delicious...
Here's what I'll tell you, Ajamila.
A month is a long time.
Somehow we lived through it together.
And I plan to keep living.
But I intend to live...
not like this...
What are you implying?
When I was alone, I only relied on myself.
But now I have you. So, be kind, provide for me.
Especially since...
I'll have to eat more soon...
Why? Planning to gain weight?
No, but I must...
Why are you looking at me like that?
We're going to have a child.
A little Ajamila.
Kamali, my girl, you've been living
with us for a year now
Did you ever feel hungry or in need?
Of course not, father.
I'm completely satisfied with my life.
I don't need money.
I love you both with all my heart
You are my treasure
but...
But what?
Just that this Brahman,
the righteous Ajamila
simply cannot
give me a son.
Did you hear that,
righteous Brahman?
Alright, alright, father!
You'll have grandchildren.
Lots of them.
Well, say something?
You don't know where
babies come from?
Or do you think you
didn't take part in this?
No, just... yes...
I'm happy Varsha, very happy...
Very happy.
I always wanted a son...
Really?
Are you telling me the truth?
You always wanted a son?
I promise, you will have a son
when the time comes. Just...
A single grain of rice won't be enough.
You understand me, Ajamila?
Look what I have...
Please, buy it...
It's for puja, paraphernalia...
Maybe you'll buy? No...
Look... it's very cheap...
Look, good paraphernalia.
Almost new... Buy them?!
Dear sir!
I want to offer you
a very valuable item.
Well, if you don't want it,
nevermind. I'll go.
Wait... Ajamila, is that you?!
Haven't seen you in a while
but I heard...
about your wife, father
but I understand...
You don't understand...
No one understands me!
When I was good
in people's eyes,
everyone greeted me,
were happy to see me.
Hello, Ajamila!
Will you perform a ritual for us?
But when I started living the way
I want, what happened?
Everyone stopped even looking
at me! Afraid of sin!
Yes, I am living
with the woman I love,
and want to be happy with her!
So what? Universal hatred?
Everyone wanted the right Ajamila,
but I want to be myself!
Can I do anything
for you, Ajamila?
Buy this from me.
You have no money?
Please just buy.
I'll get food for my family.
That's why I came here.
Please take it.
Thank you.
There!